Wayne Mitchell

Junior Software Developer

(480) 931-1131 | wayne.mitchell.1127@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

Summary

Hard Skills:

Full stack developer, specializing in front-end development platforms and libraries. Troubleshooting digital, analog circuits to component level, Knowledge of all electronic troubleshooting equipment, voltage ohms amp meters, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, Redux, Jquery, JSON, Mongoose, Express, and Nodejs, WordPress. Reading Electronics Schematics, Troubleshooting digital analog circuits to component level. Computer hardware, software installation and upgrades.

Soft Skills:Communication | Creative Thinking | Adaptability | Problem Solving | Time Management | Networking | Leadership

Work Experience:

Jr. Software Developer | January 2023 - Present Banyan Labs

- Develops processes and procedures, curriculum, and training for onboard Banyan Labs.
- Create full stack projects using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, REACT & Node.js
- Networking and building relations to create and solidify Key members responsible for rebuilding websites.

Xeriom Inc. 2014-2017

Phoenix, Az

Structured Cabling Technician

- Installation of cable infrastructure (CAT5/E, CAT6, and Fiber)
- Dress and route cable into IT closets, modular furniture, and other work area outlets
- Cable pathway installation (J-hooks, D-rings, cable trays, and ladder racks)
- Cable management (dressing and labeling)
- Cable Termination (Patch Panel, Jacks, Keystones, RJ-45/Modular Plug)
- Wireless Access Point (WAP), Fiber ONT, and Network Switch installation
- IT Closet Builds (Data rack, ladder rack, cable tray, patch panel, sleeves, 110/66 blocks)
- Fiber splicing, installation, and testing (Fluke and OTDR experience)
- Read and follow blueprints set for installation
- Follow safety guidelines and protocols (Proper PPE, clean up jobsite, OSHA)
- Manage teams to effectively complete large-scale commercial projects

Intel Corp. | 2012 - 2014

Responsible for performing electronics tests as directed by drawings, schematics, and manuals on electronic components and assisting in other mechanical assembly operations as required

- Electronics or digital circuitry.
- Experience with end-user computer skills and navigation.
- Schematic/wiring diagram reading.
- Electronic systems troubleshooting and maintenance.
- Testing, repairing and troubleshooting faulty electronic equipment down to a component using available schematics, Technical data and test equipment.
- Operations, mechanics, nuclear, weapons systems and field service.
- Experience working in a semiconductor manufacturing fab in process, equipment, operations or assembly

Education | Certification:

Certificate: Full Stack Development

Persevere Coding Boot Camp | 2020-2021

Montana State University / Associate's Degree Computer and Electronics Technologies 1995 - 1997, Billings Mt

ITT Technical College / Bachelor's Degree Electronics Engineering Technologies 1997 - 2000, Albuquerque NM